# **Chaitra Neelakanta**

# **Quality Assurance Analyst - FreedomPay Inc**

Devon, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Chaitra-Neelakanta/4ace7b269a7e81c1

- 5+ years of techno functional experience in IT industry; 4+ years in Software Testing in Agile methodology with Banking domain.
- Understanding Requirements, Test Design, Test Automation, Defect Reporting & Tracking, Regression, Test Status Reporting and Test Closure Activities.
- Experience in Both Manual Testing and Automation Testing
- Familiar with SDLC, STLC and Agile methodology.
- Good exposure in Requirements and analysis.
- Experience in Sanity, GUI, Functional, System, Web and Regression Testing.
- Involvement in preparation of Test scenarios, Test cases and executing the same.
- Test results analysis, sending suggestions and defects.
- Good exposure on Bug Life Cycle.
- Good knowledge in using of QTP integrated environment (Frameworks, Synchronization, Data Table, Actions, Recovery scenarios etc.)
- PL/SQL developer for FLEXCUBE core.
- Commitment, result oriented and interested to learn new technologies.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Quality Assurance Analyst**

FreedomPay Inc - Radnor, PA - April 2016 to Present

- Identify test requirements from specifications, map test case requirements and design test coverage plan.
- Documented and maintained functional test cases and other test artifacts like the test data, data validation, harness scripts and automated scripts.
- Executed and evaluated manual test cases and report test results.
- Reviewed functional and design specifications to ensure full understanding of individual deliverables.
- Hold and facilitated test plan/case reviews with cross-functional team members.
- Identified any potential quality issues per defined process and escalated potential quality issues immediately to the person in-charge.
- Ensured that validated deliverables meet functional and design specifications and requirements.
- Isolated, replicated, reported defects and verified defect fixes.
- Experience in both the creation and execution of both positive and negative functional and regression test scripts across multiple platforms and systems that include web based enterprise applications such as API web service calls, custom developed in-house applications, and third-party integrated applications.
- · Working in a tightly version-controlled and process oriented financial corporate environment.
- Experience in complete testing lifecycle including test plan creation, management, & execution and performing defect management, including defect aging and resolution activities to ensure adherence to quality assurance goals and guidelines.

# **Quality Assurance Analyst**

CMC, Inc - Wilmington, DE - August 2015 to April 2016

Helped in design, develop and implement test plans, scripts and tools using the detailed business requirements document provided by the business analysts.

- Worked with business and technology leads to identify the appropriate data for testing, and prepare that data for the test cases.
- Assisted Application Developers and technical support staff in identifying and resolving problems.
- Performed the tests in both the QA and contingency/backup environments.
- Worked with client in UAT to remediate and manage defects incurred in UAT

## **Test Engineer**

InnoCom, Inc - Bridgewater, NJ - January 2013 to February 2015

Efficient testing and planning of the test cases.

- Testing the application with user data with the guidance of different test cases.
- Conducted Module and System level Testing.
- Effectively executed prepared Test Scenarios by using QTP.
- Regression testing was performed after each new build of the application.
- Creating and adding the object repository in QTP.
- Prepared Functional Test cases based on Requirements & Specifications as a Business Analyst.
- Designed Test Scripts by using VB Script.
- Executed scripts in Verify, Debug and Update mode.
- Generated Test Data to validate requirements.
- Interacted with developers on various issues relating to software defects.
- Created and maintained defect reports using QC.

## **Business Applications Developer**

Oracle Financial Services Software Limited - Bangalore, Karnataka - March 2010 to March 2012

Worked for multiple banking clients across geographical locations including Americas, Latin America, India and UAE

- Testing the application with user data with the guidance of different test cases.
- Preparing the test plans and test cases.
- Performed UAT (User Acceptance Testing)
- Designed the Test Cases for Multimode collection transaction, Payments & Collections (PC), Generic Interface, Multimode, Demand Drafts etc.
- Developed codes for Utility payments (UP), MM and DD also worked on developing business cases and test cases for the modules such as new Web Branch, DD, MM screens.
- Tested the interfacing items for salary files upload (Outgoing files and Incoming files).
- Providing support to implementation teams in resolving the bugs and enhancing the functionality of application on change of client's requirement in the release.
- Provided support in testing phase of the project and fixing issues.
- Prepared and executed test plans (UTP) for required enhancements.

#### IT Analyst

IBM India Pvt Ltd - Bangalore, Karnataka - January 2010 to March 2010

Analysis of new business requirements and major developments.

- Worked extensively with vendors to resolve high priority issues.
- Maintained accurate reports and documented it accordingly.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **B.E in Computer Science & Engineering**

Visveswaraiah Technological University

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# **SKILLS**

- PL/SQL, MySQL, Java, Java Script, VB Script
- JIRA, HP QC, QTP, UFT, TFS, Bugz, IBM clearcase, PL/SQL Developer, FileZilla, WinScp, XMLspy, MS office suite, OFSS RADTOOL, Navicat, Putty, SOAP UI